paltalk.com 2019-12-28

# Privacy Policy | Paltalk

Paltalk values our users privacy and protection of their data, we build our apps and operate our business with this in mind.

Paltalk is a property of PeerStream Inc. who also operates Camfrog, TinyChat, Ribbit, Pack, Firetalk, and Vumber.  Your services are provided by Peerstream Inc. who also acts as a data controller for your information.

This privacy policy applies to all of Paltalk’s services.  By using Paltalk you agree to this Privacy Policy as well as our [Terms of Service](http://www.paltalk.com/terms).

As part of providing a great experience for you this sometimes requires us to collect personal information from you. We have done our best to give you control and access to your data where possible and we want you to be aware how that data is being used.  This policy will cover:

  * What information we may collect about you

  * What we may do with the information we collect about you;

  * Whether we share your information with anyone else

  * How we use cookies on our site

  * Where we store your information

  * How we keep your information secure

  * Your rights in relation to your information

At PeerStream Inc. we take your privacy seriously. We operate on the principle that your personal information belongs to you and only you can decide who you want to share it with and why. This is fundamental to the way we work and we’re committed to providing a secure environment for you to store your personal information and share it with others when you want to.

 **INFORMATION YOU VOLUNTARILY PROVIDE**

To register and interact with members on the site, many times you will be prompted to share information with us to improve your experience while using the product.  Some of the information you may share with us includes:

  * User nickname
  * E-mail address
  * Address or location information
  * Birthdate
  * Gender
  * Interests
  * Payment information
  * Photos
  * Personal description
  * Shared social network details
  * Information to customer support
  * Mobile Number
  * Name
  * Real-time or recorded video and audio

We primarily use this information to help other users find and connect with you, if you want to update this information you can visit [My Paltalk](https://commerce.paltalk.com/mpt/MyPalTalkHome.jsp) at any time to do so.  If you specifically desire, we will use your social networking data to allow you to create an account with data you have on another site. Your payment information is used when you decide to purchase premium parts of the Service. Information shared with customer support will be used solely to address the issue(s) you have brought to our attention.

 **INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU AND YOUR DEVICE**

When you use Paltalk and interact with our services, we may use technology to collect information about your activity.  Some of the data that is collected while using the website and mobile/desktop clients may include:

  * IP address

  * Type of browser you use

  * Number of sessions per browser/client on each device

  * Type of device and operating system

  * Referrer information

  * Local language

  * Actions taken while in the client or on the website

  * Device identifiers

We use this information to help tailor your experience for your device/language.  We also use this information to help prevent fraud as well as identify service issues.

 **THIS IS WHAT WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

We use the information you provide to us to:

  * Enable us to provide the Services

  * Ensure that our apps/website are presented in an effective manner for you and for your device

  * Provide you with marketing information about us and our services [Opt out here](https://commerce.paltalk.com/mpt/MyPalTalkHome.jsp)

  * Notify you about changes to Paltalk

  * Carry out our obligations arising out of the Terms of Service

  * Defend our servers against malicious attacks

We try to be as careful as possible when using your data.  Anywhere we take in personal data or perform actions we feel may be optional or objectionable to you, we will ask for your consent which can also be revoked at a later date.  We are always looking to improve and as we identify data that falls into this category will continue to add new messaging to you so you are always aware of when we take in your data and how we process it.

 **OUR USE OF AGGREGATED AND ANONYMIZED INFORMATION**

We may share anonymized usage data which does not identify you specifically with third parties.  We may combine your data with those of other users of PeerStream Inc. and share this information in aggregated and anonymized form with third parties to help us improve the design and delivery of our software tools, increasing the effectiveness for all users.

 **THIS IS WHO WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION WITH**

We work with 3rd parties to help with many things including sharing information with you, helping us support you, preventing fraud, protecting our infrastructure, and providing a better experience for you.

We are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal or regulatory obligation or request, and/or to protect the safety of our other users.  

Some of our advertising partners may deploy their own tracking or cookies not administered by PeerStream Inc.  These technologies are subject to our advertisers’ Privacy Policies. You can learn more about this below under the Cookies, Pixels and Local Storage section.

When processing payments third-party processors receive the information needed to verify and authorize your credit card or other payment information and to process your order. In addition, we may disclose information to third parties to verify the authenticity of any financial transaction involving our company or to update your billing information.

Below is a non-exhaustive list of third parties we work with. We may work with third parties not listed below or stop working with the third parties listed below.

  * Facebook
  * Google
  * Google Analytics
  * Flurry
  * Branch.io
  * Apsalar
  * VWO
  * PostUp
  * Intercom
  * Sift Science
  * Kickbox.IO
  * Stripe
  * Avangate
  * PayPal

 **OUR USE OF COOKIES, PIXELS AND LOCAL STORAGE**

Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored on your computer, mobile phone or other device.  Pixels are small blocks of code on web pages that do things like allow another server to measure viewing of a web page and are often used in connection with cookies. HTML5 Local Storage is a small database located inside your browser which web pages can use to store data to speed up their processing. We may use all three technologies from time to time to help improve your browsing experience.

Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, storing your preferences, and generally improving your experience on Paltalk  Cookies make the interaction between you and Paltalk faster and easier. Cookies and other things like local storage also help us authenticate you to deliver personalized content to you.

Please refer to your device’s help material to learn what controls you can use to remove or block cookies.   **Please remember that if you do this, it may affect your ability to use Paltalk**.  As you use your device, you will encounter third parties that make use of cookies and similar technologies.  We are not responsible for those third parties or what they may place on your device or in your browser.

If you are a user who is protected under the European GDPR you have the ability to manage your cookies here.

 **KEEPING INFORMATION SECURE**

The information you provide to us is stored on servers owned and operated by Amazon Web Services, Inc.  More information on this provider is available at[ ](https://aws.amazon.com/)[https://aws.amazon.com](https://aws.amazon.com/).  We use many best practice security measures to keep this data safe including private networking, firewalling, role-based access controls, authentication, backups, and monitoring.  When your data is moved off of our servers for any reason we leverage the best means available to us to make sure your data is secure in transit.

 **HERE ARE YOUR RIGHTS**

We think it is important that you are able to control your personal information.

 _For our European users who are protected by the GDPR:_

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes.  You can exercise your right to prevent such processing at any time by contacting us at support@paltalk.com.

The law gives you the right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you.  We may request additional information about you to verify your identity before we do such. We will supply, correct or delete personal information about you in our files.  In addition, you may request rectification or erasure of personal information as well as the restriction of processing of your personal information. We will comply with your requests in accordance with the applicable law.

If you wish to complain about the processing of your personal information then please contact us first, but if we do not satisfactorily deal with your complaint, then you may contact the Information Commissioner.

 _For our users not covered under GDPR:_

You may contact our support staff [here](https://support.paltalk.com/general) who will work with you to answer questions and take action to protect your privacy.

 **THIRD PARTY PROPERTIES ACCESSED FROM PALTALK**

Paltalk may contain links to and from the online properties of third parties.  If you follow a link to any of these online properties, please note that these online properties have their own privacy policies which will govern the use of any personal information that they process.  Please check these policies carefully before you click on any links and/or submit any personal information to these online properties.

 **CHANGE OF CONTROL**

If the ownership of our business changes, we may transfer your information to the new owner so they can continue to operate Paltalk and provide services.  The new owner will be obliged to comply with this Policy.

 **CHANGES TO OUR POLICY**

Any changes we may make to this Policy will be posted on this page.  Where it makes sense because the changes are material, we will notify you by e-mail or in another appropriate manner such as when you next interact with Paltalk.

 **SURVEYS AND PROMOTIONS**

From time-to-time, we may request information from you via surveys, contests or sweepstakes. Participation is completely voluntary. Information collected in any sweepstakes or contest may be used as set forth in this Policy and as described in the official rules, such as to notify the winners, award prizes, and file winners’ information, as required by law. Survey information will be used for the purposes of the survey.

 **ARBITRATION**

Any disputes under this Privacy Policy will be resolved in accordance with binding arbitration as outlined in the [Terms of Service](http://www.paltalk.com/terms).

 **TARGETING AND TRACKING**

We may use Tracking Technologies to deliver content, including ads, relevant to your interests on the Services and third-party sites based on how you interact with our advertisements or content, and to track the content you access.

To better understand your purchasing preferences, we may also use third-party vendors that provide tracking tools that recognize and collect usage and interest information across the sites you’ve visited from your various Devices. When you visit the Services on a specific Device, a unique ID is created for that Device which may be based on your hashed (de-identified) email address. This allows us and our third party vendors to deliver relevant product recommendations, personalized content and advertising to you based on your interests gathered across multiple sites. This data may be combined with the same information from another browser or Device if you use multiple browsers or Devices. Third party tracking tools might also obtain information about other applications that you have downloaded to your mobile Device, the websites you visit and other information about you or your Device in order to analyze and serve anonymous targeted advertising on the Services and elsewhere.

 **INTERNET ADVERTISING**

We or our advertising partners may use Tracking Technologies to collect Information about your visits over time and across the Services and other third-party websites and combine that information with other information received from other sources, in order to serve more targeted advertising to you. For example, we use Google interest based cookies to serve personalized ads to you. Our ad partners automatically receive your IP address or Device identifier when this happens. Their tools may also limit the number of times you see the same ad and help measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. These third parties may also use information gathered from your use of the Services to serve targeted, interest-based advertisements from other advertisers to you on third-party websites and applications.

The Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) has also made available for consumers tools on which you can register your choices not to be tracked by participating advertising networks or companies in the collection and use of your online activities. These are (1) The DAA [Consumer Choice Page for Mobile Web ](http://www.aboutadsd.info/choices/)(at [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ ](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)) and (2) DAA [AppChoices ](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices)(at <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>), which is a mobile app that allows you to opt out of the collection and use of cross-app data, other than for permitted uses, by listed third-party AppChoices participants. You may opt out of mobile-app targeted advertising ads from any or all of the listed participating advertising networks. You can download the free mobile app from an app store available on your mobile platform. When you opt out with a particular participating advertising network, the mobile app adds your device identifier to that participant’s opt-out list. The participant advertising network is then notified to block the device identifiers on the opt-out list.

You can also prevent your receipt of interest-based ads on websites by deleting and declining cookies in your browser(s). Note that your opt-out choice is applied only to the browser from which you make the choice.

Some newer mobile device operating systems allow you to limit the use of information to deliver interest-based advertising in mobile applications, or your mobile web browser may provide a “Do Not Track” browser setting which will notify those ad servers and networks who recognize the signals to refrain from sending you interest-based ads to your mobile device. You can check the settings on your device for such options in your device’s operating system. Alternatively, you may wish to download the TrustE mobile application and/or the Digital Alliance “App Choices” mobile application and follow the instructions provided.

If you opt-out of receiving targeted ads on our Services, you may continue to receive advertising and promotional messages after you opt-out, but they will not be customized or personalized to you based on your use of our Services.

We disclaim the accuracy and reliability of third-party notices and choice mechanisms.  We disclaim responsibility for noncompliance of others.

 **CONTACTING US IS EASY AND WE WANT TO HEAR FROM YOU**

We really do welcome any questions, comments, and requests you may have regarding this Policy.  You can contact us by support@paltalk.com
